Hi my name is Adam Bowling, I'm representing the Christian Martial Arts Association.
I'm here to talk to you about the aspects of the Tigery Style.
Tamo develop the five animals in mind that everyone is not the same styles.
Keeping this in mind, he knows that the tiger was also a larger animal than most of the other animals and the tiger's techniques would not be something that a smaller person would be able to use.
The tiger was use as a more of a bone-crushing, breaking, pinning to the ground type of technique.
The tiger's techniques were head on, they were for someone who is stronger, and fast and the techniques often show that, for example we do a technique called tiger on guard, tiger crouches, tiger strikes to the throat.
Tiger strikes to the throat is a straight on attack.
That aspect, this aspect of tiger shows that the person that I'm going to be coming against is either smaller than me or close to my size.
This is not a technique you would do to someone who is much bigger than you.
This would be a risky technique for someone who's small on a bigger person.